Daniel Avila

Senior Software Enginieer

CONTACT

EMAIL

daniel.avila@rottay.com

MOBIL

(+54) 1138702142

INFO

DATE OF BIRTH 23 / 04 / 90 NATIONALITY

Argentina



Profile

👋 Hi! I'm Daniel, an Argentine Systems Engineer with over 12 years of experience working in the backend, frontend, and AWS Cloud Services.

I enjoy working on projects that really make a difference, building things that have an impact on users. In that sense, I have performed in different roles and technologies; I adapt to the team's needs.

I have extensive experience working remotely with teams distributed in Latin America, the United States, and Europe. I am a team player; I am always willing to innovate and learn new technologies.



Education

Systems Engineering, National Technological University, Buenos Aires.

March 2010 - May 2017



English Spanish



Java

Node JS

Golana

React

Angular

Next

Amazon Web Services

Microservices

CI/CD

Docker

Kubernetes

GraphQL

Postgres / SQL

MongoDB / DynamoDB















Employment History



Founder & CTO at Rottay; Remote Work

2018 - act

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Migration of On-Premise Environments to AWS Cloud.
- ➤ Automation of trading strategies in Tradingview with Pine Script.
- ➤ SaaS Development Services → architecture design, development, and deployment of multi-user Applications.
- ➤ Design, development, and support of High availability Cloud solutions for Web and Mobile Applications.
- ➤ Interactive Voice Response (IVR) → Automate frequent responses allowing the customer to selfmanage their queries, create personalized greetings, collect voice and DTMF comments, routing to operators, management of Customer Service queues.

Realized tasks:

- » Direct contact with the client. Budgets and estimation of project deadlines.
- » Software Architecture design, development and code reviews.
- » Management tasks; planning, creating, and tracking tickets in Jira.

Technologies used:

Java / JavaScript / Golang / Pine Script / Docker / RDS / DynamoDB / Lambda / EKS / API Gateway / Route 53 / SNS / SQS / S3 / EC2 / CloudTrail / CloudWatch / IAM / Cognito / VPC / CloudFront / CodeStar / CodePipeline / AWS AppSync / Asterisk / IVR.





Security Scorecard

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Evolutionary development of the Marketplace UI
- ➤ Third-party app integrations with the company services → Slack, Jira, MS Teams, Zapier, Salesforce Cloud, Zendesk, etc.
- > Workflow automation to notify users or make changes within the portfolios of each customer.
- ➤ Micro FrontEnds with Webpack Module Federation to develop and deploy UI business subdomains in an isolated way.

Realized tasks:

- » Design and validation (Ajv) of the manifest schema for publishing apps.
- » Event subscriptions with RxJS.
- » Development and maintenance of the Rule Builder, to automate processes.

Technologies used:

React / Redux / NodeJs / MongoDB / Postgres / Jenkins / AWS Services / Docker / Webpack.



! INTRANET

2021

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Migration the Intranet from Ruby to Nextjs to unify the stack with the rest of the applications.
- ➤ Security improvements, validations by role, option to force 2FA, share session between the new Intranet and the platform.
- \blacktriangleright Generation of logs for Auditing \rightarrow Datadog integration to track each change made by users.
- > Support and continuous improvement of the product.

Realized tasks:

- » Develop a Nextjs application considering the Company's UI/UX standards.
- » Configuration and development of an Apollo GraphQL server.
- » Configuration of Jenkins and Dockerize development environments.

Technologies used:

NextJs / NodeJs / React / Ruby / GraphQL / MongoDB / Postgres / Jenkins / AWS Services / Docker / Datadog.



Team leader at Indeed: Contractor Work.

2020 - 2021

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Design and development of the Notification System to centralize communication with users in a single service.
- ➤ Survey and documentation of all sub-systems that interact with users, either via App (Push Notification) or Email (AWS SNS), and incorporate them into the solution provided.

Realized tasks:

- » Preparation of performance reports presenting to HR.
- » Coordinate and delegate team tasks, code reviews.
- » Documentation of the Architecture and integrations carried out.
- » Coordinate with the different sectors of the company the change of responsibility for sending notifications to users.

Technologies used:

Java / AWS SQS / AWS SNS / Jenkins / MongoDB / Jira Management Tool / Datadog / Docker / Bash / AWS DynamoDB / AWS RDS / AWS S3 / AWS Cloudfront.

Notes:

<u>Contractor</u>: Work for a specific goal or fixed period of time.







DevOps at Sage Armstrong, Contractor Work.

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Development of an on-premise version of the product using Docker.
- ➤ Replacement of the User Authentication module from CAS/SAML 1.1 to Keycloak.
- ➤ Development of the Licensing module using License 3j.
- ➤ Migration AWS S3 Buckets to Minio.
- ➤ Integration with Salesforce.

Realized tasks:

- » Updating the Authentication Services of each sub-system.
- » Migration users from MongoDB to Keycloak.
- » Extraction of logs and current status of each container.
- » Code obfuscation with ProGuard.
- » Initialization Script (a single command initializes all containers and validates the license).
- » Documentation for developers and installation tutorials for customers.

Technologies used:

Docker / Bash / Java / Drupal / Javascript / AWS Services / MongoDb / Postgres / Keycloak / Minio / Rabbit / SAML / CAS / ProGuard / L3j.



Team leader at Sancor Salud, Remote Work.

2019 - 2020

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Architecture design and development of the Company line.
- > Coordination of tasks and deliverables with Product.

Realized tasks:

- » Estimation of development times, task delegation among team members, and code review.

Technologies used:

Java 8 / Angular 6 / MySql Server / Maven / Hibernate / Auth0 / AWS S3 / Datadog.



Senior Software Engineer at Paquery, Contractor Work .

2019

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Migration of a monolithic Java Application to microservices in Node.
- ➤ Support of existing applications, server, and database maintenance.
- ➤ Cloud Architecture Design with AWS.

Realized tasks:

- » Integration of Here Maps.
- » Replacement of postal codes by Polygonal Zones.
- » Minimum path between destinations, optimal path considering traffic statistics and inclement weather.
- » Conversion of addresses into geo-coordinates and vice-versa.
- » Dockerize environments and database migration to AWS RDS.
- » Cloud Architecture \rightarrow IAM, AWS Cognito, AWS Route 53, AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS CodePipeline, AWS Fargate, AWS RDB.

Technologies used:

NodeJS / ReactJS / Java / AngularJS / Hibernate / Docker / MySql Server / AWS Services.



Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Design and develop microservices to calculate life insurance contributions based on age, salary, type of job, smoker, family group, etc.
- ➤ Development of life insurance claims management system.

Realized tasks:

- » Development and performance improvement of APIs, using Hibernate Criteria.
- » Integration of Swagger to the system for the documentation of endpoints.
- » Creation of test for all the CRUD of the System and the most important processes with Katalon Studio.
- » QA Automation \rightarrow CI/CD/AWS CodePipeline.
- » Dockerization of development environments.

Technologies used:



2018

Functional Requirements:

➤ Development of a Web/Mobile Application that serves as a support for Lyme patients. The application will notify the dose and schedule of each medication in a personalized way. Alerting relatives and doctors in case of non-compliance.

Realized tasks:

- » Choice of Architecture (AWS), model design and development.
- » Coordinate and lead a distributed team of people.
- » Periodic demos with the client.

Technologies used:

NodeJS / React / React Native / AWS AppSync / AWS Lambda / AWS Cognito / AWS DynamoDB / AWS SES.



Senior Software Developer at Credicoop Bank, Capital Federal.

2014 — 2018

Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Migration of the IVR'S of the Credicoop, Segurcoop, Cabal Card, and COTO Bank from native Asterisk to JAVA, to reduce the number of calls handled by the Customer Service Call Center, automating the most commonly performed tasks, such as:
- → Activation of Credit and Debit cards.
- → Reports of loss/theft of cards.
- \rightarrow PIN generation.
- \rightarrow Account/Card balance request.
- → Transfers between own accounts.
- \rightarrow Buy dollars.
- \rightarrow Consultation of Aerolineas Plus points.
- ➤ Generation of logs that are easy to use by the BI sector.

Realized tasks:

- » Analysis, design of the Software Architecture, development and production start-up.
- » Maintenance and Support of service queues to the Customer Service Call Center.
- » Coordination of tasks between the Technology and Product management.
- » Internal training on Asterisk and IP Telephony.

Technologies used:

Java / Hibernate / Maven / Asterisk / AngularJS / PHP / Linux / Perl / Python / MySQL Server / Oracle / Bash / C / MongoDB.





Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Migrate the current employee management system from Flex to Angular2.
- ➤ Enhance the employee management system to digitize forms and documents. Application of OCR techniques to collect information.
- ➤ Verify that employees have entered all required information to the employee management system when accessing the premises.

Realized tasks:

- » Prepare the project planning.
- » Prepare the documentation.
- » Development and testing.

Technologies used:

Java / Spring Boot / Maven / MySql Server / MongoDB / Tomcat / Bash / FLEX / Angular 2.



Senior Software Developer at Fiat, Contractor Work.

2016 — 2017

Functional Requirements:

- ▶ Provide a system which handles the access of employees to the factory.
- ➤ Register and manage the working time of each employee.
- ➤ Provide automated reporting on access and presence of employees.
- ➤ Generate anomalies reports and send alerts to those responsible for the area.

Realized tasks:

- » Analysis, Time estimates, Development and Documentation.
- » Make demos in the client's office.

Technologies used:

Java / Spring Boot / Maven / Oracle / Tomcat / Bash / Flex .



Senior Software Developer at Puente Hermanos, Capital Federal.

2012 — 2014

Functional Requirements:

- $\ensuremath{\mathtt{x}}$ Improve the general user experience of the customer portal.
- x Add trading functions to the customer portal.
- x Integrate with the NASDAQ trading platform.

Realized tasks:

- » Design and Development Internal pages.
- » Prepare tests using Selenium.
- » Include bootstrap so that the system is available on all devices.

Technologies used:







Functional Requirements:

- ➤ Design and Preparation of Macros, Validations, and Dynamic Tables in Excel, in order to provide information to those responsible for keeping the company's accounts.
- ➤ Design and Development of the Zika Inventory System. Notification by email in case of non-compliance with the return date.

Realized tasks:

- » Training to other Employees of the Company on the use and elaboration of macros in Excel.
- » Analysis and coding of Inventory System.

Technologies used:

Java / JSP / MySQL Server / Office Package.



Courses

Big Data, Apache Hadoop, UTN FRBA

February 2017 - May 2017

Itil® Foundation V3, UTN FRBA

June 2016 - October 2016

Project Management PMP, UTN FRBA

May 2016 —October 2016

Certificate Standard English, EF

87 / 100 (C1 Advanced)